Farhana Shahid

Research Interests

My research interests encompass various multidisciplinary divides with particular focus on Human-Computer Interaction (HCI). Currently I am working at the intersection of data science, applied machine learning, social computing, and ubiquitous computing to address health related issues of marginalized communities. My research focuses on technology mediated, data-driven yet human-centered approaches to create new values having sustainable outcomes for people.

Appointments _____

Brac University Dhaka, Bangladesh

LECTURER May 2018 – Present

Eastern University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

LECTURER Sep 2017 – Apr 2018

Education

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

MASTERS OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING 2017 – 2019

GPA: 4.00 out of 4.00

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering 2013 – 2017

GPA: 3.74 out of 4.00

Academic Awards

- 2016 University Merit Scholarship, Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
- 2015 **Dean's List Award**, Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
- 2015 First runner up: Poster Presentation Session, Esonance, Islamic University of Technology
- 2012 Champion: Science Olympiad, Inter College Science Festival, Holy Cross College
- 2011 First runner up, 4th Bangladesh Chemistry Olympiad
- 2011 Secondary School Merit Scholarship, Education Board of Dhaka

Publications

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Farhana Shahid**, Shahinul Hoque Ony, Takrim Rahman Albi, Sriram Chellappan, Aditya Vashistha, and A. B. M. Alim Al Islam. 2020. Learning from Tweets: Opportunities and Challenges to Inform Policy Making During Dengue Epidemic. In *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*. Vol. 4, No. CSCW1, Article 65 (May 2020).
- 2. **Farhana Shahid**, Wasifur Rahman, Anika Binte Islam, Nipi Paul, Nabila Khan, Mohammad Saifur Rahman, Md Munirul Haque, and A. B. M. Alim Al Islam. 2019. Two Tell-tale Perspectives of PTSD: Neurobiological Abnormalities and Bayesian Regulatory Network of the Underlying Disorder in a Refugee Context. In *Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies*. Vol. 3, No. 3, Article 101 (September 2019).

Teaching Experience _____

THEORY COURSE INSTRUCTOR

- Computer Graphics (Spring 2020, Fall 2019, Summer 2019, Spring 2018)
- Digital Logic Design (Spring 2020, Summer 2018)
- Programming Language I (Fall 2019, Spring 2019, Fall 2018)
- Programming Language II (Spring 2019, Fall 2018)
- Data Structures (Summer 2019)

- Operating Systems (Spring 2018, Fall 2017)
- Mathematical Analysis for Computer Science (Fall 2017)

LAB COURSE INSTRUCTOR

- Computer Graphics (Spring 2020, Fall 2019, Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Summer 2018)
- Artificial Intelligence (Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- Object Oriented Programming (Fall 2019, Summer 2019, Spring 2019)
- Programming Language I (Summer 2019, Spring 2019, Summer 2018)
- · Algorithms (Summer 2019, Fall 2019, Summer 2018)
- Digital Logic Design (Summer 2019)
- Data Structures (Summer 2018)
- Operating Systems (Spring 2018, Fall 2017)

COURSE COORDINATOR

- Theory Course Coordinator: Computer Graphics (Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- · Lab Course Coordinator: Artificial Intelligence (Spring 2020, Fall 2019), Object Oriented Programming (Fall 2019)

STUDENTS MENTORED

UNDERGRADUATE STUDENTS

- Takrim Rahman Alvi
- Shahinul Hoque Ony

Skills_

Languages C/C++, Java, Python, MATLAB, R, PHP, Node.JS, SQL, LaTeX, Prolog, Assembly (8086), Bash/ Shell script,

CSS, and HTML5.

Web Frameworks Gatsby, ASP.NET, and Codelgniter.

Tools OpenGL, Weka, Oracle, Apache Derby, Anaconda, scikit-learn, and Word2Vec library.

Services

COMMITTEE MEMBER

2019 AI, ML, and NLP thesis panel, Brac University

2019 Course curriculum update following OBE guidelines, Brac University

2018 Semester planning, Brac University

ORGANIZING COMMITTEE

2018 5th Eastern University Math Olympiad, Eastern University

REVIEWER

2020 Asian CHI Symposium

VOLUNTEER

2015 National High School Programming Contest, Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology